he said what you said is too easy
so then i thought if i if i have to go
to paris i should teach something
difficult
so i thought i'd like to teach something
which i enjoy
and i'm sorry i cannot speak in french
m
okay uh okay
so this is a special teaching uh
i learned it from my teacher
his teacher was the teacher of this
and then my teacher talked to me
i don't think anybody ever translated it
into uh
out of tibet
so i did an english translation the
first part
and i'm teaching it to my students my
regular students in arizona
uh then i thought it would be nice uh to
translate it uh cecile is translating it
into french
and i i think it's a very important book
uh
it's not just philosophy
you can use it for your life
so last night i gave a talk to uh i
don't know 300
french business leaders
yeah
with these ideas i made a quarter
billion dollar company
and with these ideas you can have a very
beautiful relationship alexis
if you don't have a partner now you can
use these ideas to find a good partner
if you already have a good
pretty good partner you can improve them
basically they are very beautiful ideas
and you can use them to to have a happy
life
so but it's going to be difficult for
you
so for two hours we will talk about
something new
if you understand it
you can start to change your life
you can be financially comfortable
uh
you'll be a happy person
and you
i teach a lot of chinese communists
and
four days ago we taught in the
so i don't care what you are it doesn't
matter i'm just trying to
give you a tool which you can use to be
successful and happy in your
and it's life little difficult you sound
good uh so you have to focus
uh don't get sleep if you get sleepy
so this this is a poem
and it was written by the first pension
woman
uh the pentagon is like the dynamic
is
he was born in 17
he lived for 92 years
he wrote a beautiful book about dancing
there was a big war in tibet
meditation
again
so he was very brave
very beautiful
so he
he said during his meditation he began
to hear two voices in his mind
two people are arguing inside of his
mind
one is like angel one is like devil
i don't know if you have in france but
in in
in america we have this picture the
devil is here the angel is here and they
are they are trying to convince the guy
what to do
so he wrote a poem about that
oxygen money means when you came into
this room
you didn't ask carl or cecil
is there enough oxygen in this room
she's going to breathe
i don't like my friends they have big
credit card debts
and they
and
you don't have to have all this crisis
and discussion with your partner and the
headaches and mentors they purposely
want to
so i i'll is you the main idea firstly
my people are watching your people
on the planet
planet we have a special telescope
you can see through the roof of the
house
then i i saw
i was watching in the telecom
first they start to like taste like this
then they start to go like the kids are
screaming
and they start to go like this
then the husband comes home
where's dinner
then she go
she sits on the toilet with the cover
down
this is your quiet place
and she's waiting
i don't know why
she waits for a while at a time
then she takes another one i'll shoot
they don't fall on the zoo
sometimes she doesn't smile that's like
sleeping so
i i was sent from my planet
sometimes she takes another one why does
she take the second one yeah
so
so can we say sometimes it works and
sometimes it doesn't work
how many are working here
i never saw her go back to the pharmacy
to ask for half of the money back
i don't
i think it's okay
if you
do they work
you can say sometimes right
now
if uh
okay i pick on british area okay we we
gave um
pretty sure we had a big strike two
years
yeah the zombies
is
london and we talked to some of the vice
presidents
the strike finish
but when you get on the british airway
airplane
and if they say announcement
uh
sometimes the airplane works sometimes
it doesn't work
sometimes it flies sometimes it falls
down
uh
but you are strange people
you take aspirin
it's the same as getting on a plane that
you don't know if the plane will work
and it doesn't work other times in a
nutshell
that means it doesn't work
okay
if the plane flies sometimes
but the plane falls down sometimes
it means that plane doesn't work
in my planet
if it works sometimes
and it doesn't work sometimes
then it doesn't hurt
if there's an aspirin which works all
the time
but we didn't find one
so we take it i take also we take this
one hello
if somebody made an aspen that works all
the time of course we all of us will buy
it
and then inside the aspen there is
something that works
if you don't answer
whenever
is the active ingredient in half of the
pill and not in half of the pills
she said active ingredient is the thing
that works
am i right especially in
so the active ingredient doesn't work
half the time
am i right
is
what did you think because um there was
a big story that um
uh vitamins and they weren't mixed
properly
oh yeah
and so then you know what some of them
had kind of like massive
but i believe in here the active
ingredient is in each
they have different uh situations
something is different in their in their
heading
yeah
when the active ingredient works
much
you see
sometimes the active ingredient is
active and sometimes the active
ingredients know that
it's the same ingredients
we have to think we have to be scientist
scientific
why does active ingredient work
one day an active ingredient doesn't
work the next time
achievement
it's the same with your boyfriend
sometimes you kiss him
he's happy you know what sometimes you
kiss him
don't bother me
no it's true kiss nothing
we
only
we tried to do our best i said it
further
that's what you said something you said
we
we try it's the best thing we know
so really
from our in our planet
you wake up in the morning
you at that time you are thinking i want
to make him happy
he says don't
and we god used to failure
we got used to working hard and
sometimes we make money and sometimes we
don't
have a performance
we you got used to doing things half the
time they work half the time they don't
work you are like people getting on
british airways
who they see that you choose fairly
shoes or
why don't you just do something that
works
or something just do something that
works all the time
don't keep trying the thing that works
hard time doesn't work
don't pay for something
if i can tell you how to make it work
every time then it's good that you can
do it
is
that works
and
i paid
is
uh so what i what i'd like to talk about
tonight is how can we
is there a way to make your boyfriend
like a kiss every day
this is what we want to do okay
there are two
guys
in your mind
one is the other
he's
if he is successful all the time he can
make his own money
hello
right now the lounge is based
on the second maybe he's not crazy
for himself
he doesn't know
teach them how to make money
it's the lounge is saying
maybe
maybe he knows something
for sure
okay okay but already i put the virus in
your way
maybe he knows how to make my boyfriend
enjoy the kiss every time
maybe
maybe he has oxygen
can you hear the angel
who is listening to them
so there's three of us
if he's right then the whole world 6
billion people are wrong
i don't know i'll check on the internet
maybe
to watch the angel and the devil in your
mind is a special kind of meditation
so this is special meditation
meditation
maybe you should call your mother today
come on we don't have time
he's very persuasive
tonight
practice
that's a very good thing
the argument is always good
i should call my mother
to sustain this fight to keep this bike
going
we say this is a very good camera
the fight is a
the fight is a good camera
look she's busy last time you called she
look i call my mother
i call
is good camera
it's better karma than the person who
calls their mother all the time
to have a fight in your mind
if if they keep fighting that's because
he continues
someday i'm sure the angel will win
the angel always wins
in america there's a new word they say
today i feel conflicted
i didn't know what it meant
my friend told
sometimes i
close the door
and that's a very very important
is
if you can learn to listen to your mind
if you really can listen
just nobody told us in the school when
we were young they didn't say oh carl
listen to your
you can get really
good
and then you can learn many beautiful
things about yourself
yes the question was is listening the
mind
the same thing as observing those
thoughts
why is
you are trying to start a fight
okay
it's a good question
is
i'm
don't say this plane
there is active ingredients
who is the devil
the government
everybody who told you this has an
active ingredient is the dough
is
what the angel says
if you have a headache
if you want to stop the headache
find somebody else who has a headache
it's all wrong
you know that you you are thinking oh
it's too much you just call him
bad idea don't call him
there
if you think the way to make money is to
work hard and take the money from the
other companies you are
incredibly wrong
took over your mind a long time ago
you
maybe you will make money maybe you will
not
you will give the house to your kids
they will lose it in three years
they will spend all the money
that you worked your whole life
it's all
why
every city where i go they have office
ready for me
mexico city
mexico
i have five
in paris i go to the beach
i just have to buy one of these
yes
thank you
so if you
the devil wants you to work like crazy
man
he wants you to fail sometimes succeed
sometimes
he's making you crazy
is like look just
understand
is
does it work
is the active ingredient
what fixes
the cause of your headache stopped
see
if you help them simply
you put a seed in your mind
in your mind
this is the active ingredient
in you have a seat in your mind from
helping somebody with a headache the
asking will work for you
if you don't help other people with a
headache and you take 100 husband
nothing will happen
is this now
it seems crazy right
no so what's the angel's name
is the opposite
what's the devil's name i'm sorry angela
without helping another person who has a
headache this is not an aspect
is
so does a british airway plane which
falls down half the time is this a is
this a passenger airplane
i mean if you don't want the passenger
to die
is it a passenger
no it's not
is something that makes us
takes away the fear the pain and it
doesn't work half of the time so it's
not enough god bless you
beautiful
is the fastest growing manufacturing
company in the history
i work three days
because it doesn't it doesn't do
anything
all
is
one question but if i help somebody do i
need the aspirin
it's a beautiful question
it's a beautiful question okay
i have another question but it's
beautiful i'm still answering your
question right does yoga work it's clear
you get much
a lot of us are
is
yoga i hurt my shoulder this morning
very badly
i took a class at brazil
if the yoga hurts you sometimes and if
the yoga helps you sometimes
is it yoga
you get something
okay the angel says
yoga is not
what's the active ingredient in
what's the active ingredient
and
you
you are watching you are here and you
are watching the angel and the devil
talk
the devil will say
no no you don't understand
and this meditation is it meditation is
to start the fight
the angel yeah the angel is very
young the angel is very new i just put
the engine in your mouth
not very strong
is
no no i'm busy
all right i will stay here should i stay
down uh if you have a question
i can fix anything i'm like wizard of oz
okay so then you can come talk
you
okay
one is to watch your own mind
this is one meaning
that's a promising
how does it really work
come
then most people don't think like that
uh if you say uh
does he ask for more they say yeah
and you say why does it work
they will say it has an active
ingredient
that's why it works so much
oh i have a difficult question for you
do you understand what i said tonight
why because because i
taught me
you helped somebody else understand
something
that's the active ingredient
and that that's
that's the power of my word is coming
from
so the understanding you hear
in your own mind
no
is your own mind your own mind
if you help other people to understand
before your mind
understands
do you need to
if your uh help to someone is very very
very powerful you don't even need the
experts
remember uh if you help other people who
are sick very much you don't need to do
yoga your body will be strong
most of us have to do yoga
you will understand with other teachers
you can study with them i trained him
for a long time many years
i trained both of them for many years
so your own mind is not thinking it
starts by itself
the thoughts are coming into your mind
because you helped somebody before
oh
but you
but we don't understand
one day during meditation you will you
will see the injury
meditation
directly
it's very beautiful
you can do it
you can learn
after that yeah
very funny you see
do you have a
i don't know did you ever have a boss
in your job
who you didn't like
they had a boss
you do a good job for one month you make
one small mistake all they talk about
where is that complaining coming from
is the complaining boss a complaining
boss
critic
yeah she's supposed to say
and you're supposed to stand up
complaining because
your complaining was smaller than his
complaining because the seed is smaller
than the tree
he is much worse than you
it's better if you meet the boss
tomorrow
okay so it gets bigger and bigger
now
if the boss tells you you are stupid
then in your mind what will come
in the mind
even though it's
again
no no finish
he called you stupid because you called
your
brother stupid last week
then you are you are stupid
okay
if you understand the aspect
if you understand where things are
coming from
the devil says
you have to defend yourself if you take
the phone
he is stupid he read it yesterday was
talking says
why
the angel will try to talk but he's not
very strong okay
probably you will answer you are stupid
and then after 10 minutes you will
remember
10 000 workers in the world you mean
everybody
i told the businessman last night very
funny
they said one day they said we are going
on strike
by 800 workers
and i said no no in america you have to
pay uh one and a half time
i
i said you are going to stick four hours
extra for no money
everybody in green
see i clean them one by one
so understand something how can i get
your shoes
if you want to kiss your husband and he
says i'm busy with him today
and one by one you are cleaning
everything
how long did you stay in the yoga class
say two hours
your wrinkles are two hours more
right now you see this going to die
but but you can change it
it's also coming from your seats
you can you can change this into
we say if you understand this system and
if you work hard this will change into
life
because
after you change your body
when the body
by the way on our planet everybody has a
light body
and all the aspen work
i'm serious
is
last question what's
cement does not make the world heard
it's very
serious to to have this fight you you
want to have this fight
without the fight you you will just get
older
so who has to leave your mind
he has to go
the devil is the analgesic aspirin
company
if you read the text at home you can see
where what we talked about
but the devil doesn't want to lead your
mind
he wants to stay
blessed and he is not stupid he is best
friend he is very very smart
you don't have to call your mother she
won't be home
i'm happy to answer a few questions
come
you mentioned that
if you call your mother every day
you are not as strong as if the devil is
fighting with you
so if you purify yourself then
there's two kinds of people who call
their mother yeah this other doesn't get
their daughter
one first kind
they always call their brother
from the beginning
their mother taught them to call their
dangerous
the other person is the person who's
having the fight
the devil says
then
this person their mother can trust them
because this person will not change
because this person
the best teacher for alcoholics
the person who never had alcohol
problems they are not such a good
alcohol teacher
but it's a very good question
okay one more then we'll finish okay you
said mahamudra
the first meaning of mahamudra
during that time the aspen was not an
aspen lesbian
that's called the original mohammed
later
i start to talk to you
oh please before you take the aspirin
help another person
and then the fight begins
in your mind
this is called the mahamudra
but the path began the fight began
so that whole time
now it's going to start tonight
good person who understands this thing
the person
they are walking around the bus station
you can see them incredible oh they are
stunning
they make you confused
if you are a spiritual person
and if you are
confused because you have fine in here
you are close to you are close to
becoming injured
the fight comes just before you change
is kicked out
one is before you thought about it
exist
when you are talking to yourself in the
training
then the last one is when you
i love parents
and i will do anything to come here
please tomorrow asked me to come again
okay
is
it can be a relationship
i train these people for
some of them 15 20 years
and they're very very they they're
really good teachers
uh
like today last night one of the
business people had a question
a very serious question about depression
i said you have to buy him one coffee
just talk to them okay
thank you
you want jazz tomorrow or you want
indian music or you want both
okay
um
foreign
on